Student: What projects are you working on now?
And if you'd rather not talk about that, what projects
or models had you considered before that were
interesting that you didn't do?
Will Wright: You mean like what systems have I
considered modeling?
Student: Right. And also what systems are you
currently working on, if you can talk about them?
Will Wright: Oh, God… Okay, well one thing we're
working on, is a — we've been kind of interested in
our company for a long time about the idea of
data portability.
Will Wright: Really, let me back up just a little bit
here, and this might be a little bit more of an answer
than you were looking for, but…
Will Wright: Most of the game industry right now is
built on kind of the movie model. So you spend a lot
of money developing one big title, you come out with
it, you advertise it, either it goes or it dies, and
then you do the next one separate.
Will Wright: Except for sequels — the one genre that
does better than any other genre in the game industry
is sequels.
Will Wright: What we've tried to do, slowly over time,
is build our games more as a hobby model, where people
buy and collect things that relate to the last things
they collected.
Will Wright: It's like a train set: some people get into
building the hills and trees, they could care less about
the train; others get into the village, or the track
switching. Everybody comes in, takes their slant, focuses
in great detail.
Will Wright: I'd like the game industry to evolve that
way — I want the games to actually be able to have
persistent data that can move from one game to another.